you didn't build cities well the Finns the
вы города не строили вот ну фины фины
Finns specifically the Finns Not a single city
конкретно фины Ни один город не
was built what city did you build the Finns
построили какой вы город построили фины
personally the Finns city what are you what
лично фины город какой ты ты какой город
city did the Finns build What city did
построил фины Какой город построили
Helsinki Tampere build Helsinki is not your
Хельсинки Тампере Хельсинки - это не ваш
city And whose is this the Swedes built A
город А чей это это шведы построили А
got it A  what city
понял А какой вы город
did you build Hello
построили Здравствуйте Здравствуйте
Hello Hello Where are you from I am from Russia
Здравствуйте Вы откуда откуда Я с России
I can tell by your face And what city does it
я вижу по лицу А город какой Какая вам
matter to you what city you are from Ukraine I
разница какой город вы с Украины Я так
understand no I am originally from
понимаю нет сам родом из
St. Petersburg But I have been living in London for 18
санкт-петербурга Но живу в Лондоне 18
years in 2 years it will be the
лет через 2 года будет
twentieth Where  in London I'm telling you and in
двадцатое Где в Лондоне Я же говорю а в
London Well just hold on I won't
Лондоне Ну просто подержи не я вам
believe you that the flag is like that but I'm from Kazan
поверю что флаг такой но я с Казани
Okay Okay I'll tell you the city of Kazan
Ладно Хорошо скажу город Казань
is cool my father is from Yelabuga
прикольно у меня отец Елабуги родом
Holy [ __ ] Where did he live in Yelabuga Damn
Нифига себе А где он жил в Елабуге блин
How do I know he moved back When
Откуда я знаю он он переехал ещё При
Soviet Union in Leningrad to study here
Советском Союзе в Ленинград учиться тут
met my mother I was born in
встретился с мамой Я родился в
eighty-first I am now I
восемьдесят первом го Я сейчас я сейчас
am now in
нахожусь в
Yelabuga Wow  coincidence Well, yes, it's
Елабуге [__] совпадение Ну да
cool, you know what Yelabuga is
прикольно знаете чем Елабуга
famous for, drones are doing something there now
знаменито дроны там что-то сейчас делают
or what Well, no, not a drone, that's a separate
или что Ну да не Дрон это отдельный
issue, a
вопрос здесь родился
shish artist offi lesovik was born here, the one that
шиш художник офи лесовик тот что это Три
wrote Three Bears Morning in a Pine Tree yes, yes, yes,
медведя написал Утро в сосновом да да
yes, yes, that's Shishkin Yes, here he is, his role
дадада да это Шишкин Да вот он его рола
God Damn, now I understand that our
Бога Блин я теперь понимаю что у нас
dad In short, he hung this picture with these
батя Короче эту картину повесил с этими
bears and he said, damn, I
медведями и он говорил вот это блин я
think, why the hell is he fussing over it like that And
думаю нафиг что он так с ней носится А
now I understand, because Shishkin too Well, this is the Motherland,
теперь понял бо Шишкин тоже Ну это
this is the Motherland, everything Yes, now I understand I
Родина это родина всё Да теперь понял Я
say, damn, why the hell  we don't need it
говорю блин Нафига нам это короче нет
anyway These bears should be he says
всё Эти медведи должны быть он говорит
he was small with them These bears
он был маленький у них Эти медведи
were hanging in short and oh he hung it up now
висели короче и о он повесил теперь
I understand I understand I'll know thank you for
понял Понятно Буду знать спасибо что
telling me
рассказали
and not lying actually Yes I understood
а не обманываю на самом деле Да я понял
it's cool cool
это круто круто
yes my roots are also from Yelabuga  half
да мои корни тоже из Елабуги наполовину
like So it's clear understandable And you
типа Так что понятно понятно А вы
Tatar who is not I'm Ruy I'm
татарин кто нет я руй я
Russian what am I half
русский что я наполовину
Tatar
татарин
me well your ue it
меня ну ваши уэ
turns out yes it's normal They were always
получается да нормально Они всегда были
normal Well like well they  half not
нормальные Ну типа ну они наполовину не
Russian That's already
русские Это уже
good Why are they good But who do they
хорошо Почему хорошие А вот кем они себя
consider themselves to be, that's their problem, you understand I
считают это уже их проблема понимаете Я
don't insist Well, if they consider themselves
не настаиваю Ну если они считают себя
Russian, that's their problem Why do they
русскими это это их проблема Почему они
consider themselves to be who do they not understand, you don't
кем себя считают не понимаете не
understand, Russians in general, Russians are a
понимаете русские вообще русские - это
great nation, you
великая нация
understand A  if the Russians are a great
понимаете А у русских если это великая
nation they should have their own republic
нация у них должна быть своя республика
for example the Tatars are a great nation they have a
например татари Великая нация у них есть
republic We have Russia you see
республика У нас есть Россия понимаешь
it is not Russia - it is written multinational among all the peoples
так не Россия - это у всех народов
Russia is a state it is
Россия написано многонациональное
not a Russian state
Государство это не государство русское
So what so what Yes for example
Ну и что ну и что Да вот например
Tatarstan is the Republic of Tatars Chechnya is the
Татарстан - это Республика Татар Чечня -
republic of Chechens Yes and the Russians don't have
республика чеченцев Да а у русских нет
Russia no so everything together Russia Yes
Россия нет так всё вместе Россия Да
look Russia is a
смотри Россия - это го Россия - это
state of Chechens
государство чеченцев
listen young man look
слушайте молодой человек вот смотрите
here there is a bicycle Yes there are spokes there is a
вот есть велосипед Да есть спицы есть
wheel there yes and everything together  This is
колесо там есть да а всё вместе Это
a bicycle, that's the same thing, Russia is
велосипед вот тоже самое Россия есть
Tatarstan, there is Chechnya, Yes, there is Mariel, there is
Татарстан есть Чечня Да есть Мариэл есть
Re, And all together it is Russia, Yes, that's right,
ре А всё вместе это Россия Да правильно
Russia is the state of all, Russia
Россия - это государство всех Россия -
is the state of
это государство
Tatars, Yes, yes, yes, Russia is the
татар Да дада да Россия - это
state  Chechens Yes Yes Yes they can do
государство чеченцев Да Дада они мо
what you like Absolutely right Yes but
угодно правильно Абсолютно верно Да но
this is a state of all peoples of all
это государство всех народов всех
peoples like a Union like that yes a federation
народов как типа Союз такой да федераци
this is not a Federation not an Empire No no not an
это ж не Федерация не Империя Нет нет не
Empire Federation you have a Federation different
Империя Федерация у вас Федерация разные
subjects Yes look there is a
субъекты Да смотрите есть субъект
Tatar subject Well there is a Chechen
татарский Ну есть субъект чеченский
Ingush Adyghe subject  Sakha yes And where is the subject
ингушский адыгский Саха да А где субъект
Russian But all together it is Russia
русский А вот всё вместе это есть Россия
all together is the Federation Russian
всё вместе - это Федерация Российская
Federation Yes it is written in the Constitution a
Федерация Да это в Конституции написано
multinational country there is no written
многонациональная страна там не написано
what it is but there it is written how you can be
что это а там написано как можно вам
addressed Andrey Vasilyevich Andrey
обращаться Андрей Васильевич Андрей
ok Andrey not Andrey Vasilyevich you
хорошо Андрей не Андрей Васильевич вы
ask Andrey  Vasilievich let's
спроси Андрей Васильевич давайте мы
be new after all No well I'm older than you and
всё-таки новы будем Не ну я вас старше и
what am I older than you we are adults
что я вас старше по мы совершеннолетние
Let's talk to each other by name patronymic no what's
Давайте друг другу по имени отчеству нет
your
Вас как
name okay My name is Ilya Anatolyevich
зовут хорошо Меня зовут Илья Анатольевич
Ilya Anatolyevich I am Andrey Vasilievich
Илья Анатольевич Я Андрей Васильевич
Let's address Okay okay Andrey
Давайте Обращаемся Хорошо хорошо Андрей
Vasilievich I still want to tell you  I'll explain once it's
Васильевич я вам ещё раз объясняю Вот
written in it's written Russian Federation
написано в написано Российская Федерация
is equivalent to Russia is correct Yes And what does
равнозначна Россия правильно Да А причём
Russian have to do with it this is the name Russia Yes
тут русские это название Россия Да
the name of the state is the same as  European Union
название государства также как Евросоюз
Yes European Union United States of
Да Европейский союз Соединённые Штаты
America Yes and in the state of Russia there
Америки Да вот а в государстве Россия
are different Naro-arics there What else do not
есть разные Наро арики там Какая ещё не
interrupt there are different there they do not have
перебивайте там разные там у них нету
There are Irish Italians there is no
Есть ирландцы итальянцы там нет
English Republic there is
Республики английской нет Республики
no German Republic Yes
немецкой нет
that's right there are indigenous Indians
Да правильно там индейцы коренные
absolutely the same way and Russians live  on
абсолютно так же и русские живут на
foreign land they don't have their own republic nothing
чужой земле у них нет своей респу ничего
like that we live on our own land not where is
подобного мы живём на своей земле не где
your republic this is Russia is
республика ваша это есть Россия есть
Our republic no no Russia is a
Наша республика нет нет Россия - это
Federation of different subjects in your
Федерация разных субъектов у вас в
Constitution it is written Vasilyevich Andrey
Конституции написано Васильевич Андрей
Vasilyevich Who knows better me or you I am a
Васильевич Кто лучше знает я или ты я Я
lawyer  How can you know better than me
юрист Откуда ты можешь знать лучше меня
I am a lawyer I am a resident of Russia I am a lawyer so if
Я юрист я житель России Я юрист так если
you are a resident of Russia tell me Tell me
ты житель России скажи Скажи по
where it is written in the Constitution that this is a
Конституции где написано что это
Russian state Look in the Constitution of
государство рус Вот смотри в Конституции
Ukraine I read their Constitution it
Украины Я читал ихнюю Конституцию
says this is a state of the Ukrainian
написано это государство украинского
people in the Constitution of Russia it says this is a
народа в Конституции России написано это
state of a multinational people  it is not
государство многонационального народа не
written Russian Russian people in the
написано русского русского народа в
Constitution No Andrey you are distorting
Конституции Нет Андрей ты передёргивает
distorting so tell me where in the
передёргивает так скажи где в
Constitution is it written the thing is I
Конституции записа дело в том я тебе
will tell you now about Ukraine you say
сейчас скажу про Украину ты говоришь
Ukraine citizens of Ukraine They  all
Украина граждане Украины Они все
Ukrainians you understand it turns out it is not
украинцы понимаешь это получается не
a nationality it turns out it is eh
национальность это получается е ещ раз
look again in Ukraine it is written this is the Constitution of the
смотри Украине написано это Конституция
Ukrainian people Show me where it is
украинского народа Покажи где где
written in Russia that the Russian people
написано в России что русского народа
Vasilevich Vasilich there is no such
василевич Василич нет такой
nationality Ukrainian is y Let there be no
национальности украинец это й Пусть нету
Russians there is no such nationality
так и русских нету такой национальности
semi Calm down There are no Russians
полу Успокойся Русских нет украинцев
there are no Ukrainians  we are not all I don't care about
нету нас не всё мне всё равно на
Ukrainians I look I'm from St. Petersburg
украинцев я смотри я сам родом из Питера
I don't care what Ukrainians and Belarusians are there
мне всё равно что там украинцы белорусы
You tell me where our Russian republic is
Ты скажи где наша русская республика
Vasily on
Василь на
ne ba Don't interfere with the flour go don't distract
не ба Не мешай муку рить иди не отвлекай
her You who OTV who your granny in short what
её Ты кого ОТВ кого твою бабу короче что
she you  distracts Me and the guy are
она тебя отвлекает Мы тут с мужиком
fine here Well there's a woman there
нормально Ну там тебе баба что-то
saying something to you quietly there's no woman here
говорит тихо никакой здесь бабы нету ты
what are you doing Who is this no no one it
что А кто это да нет никого тебе
seemed to you someone already told
показалось у тебя уже кто тебе говорил
you not to you the woman told you nothing there no
не тебе баба говорила ти ничего там мне
one is telling me to you the woman is in the way
никто не говорит тебе баба короче мешает
nobody tells you it seemed to you already you
никто не говорит тебе показалось те уже
understand you are some kind of you go to a psychiatrist
ре понимаешь ты какой-то ты к психиатру
Vasilich Explain to me look here
обратись Василич Объясни мне смотри вот
for example, Saint Petersburg for us is not a
например санкт-петербург у нас это не
city of Russians, it is a city of all Uzbeks and
город русских это город всех узбеков
Tajiks, everyone lives there Vasilyevich Look,
таджиков там все живут Васильевич Смотри
you see a field, name at least one
вот ты видишь поле назви хоть один
Russian city, name a Russian city, you see
русский город назви русский город види
Well, you see a field, you see holes there,
Хорошо ты видишь поле видишь норы там
name a Russian city, there are gophers there, there are
Назови русский город там Суслики там
gophers, as if  you may not see them
сусликов их как будто бы ты их не видишь
but they are there name a Russian
Но они там есть назви руский город
city name at least one Russian city Moscow
Назови русский город хоть один Москва
will suit you no Moscow is a city
устроит тебя нет Москва - это город
Tajiks Chechens are there all here Grozny is a
таджики чеченцы там все вот Грозный
Chechen city there are 98% Chechens and what in
чеченский город там 98% чеченцы И что в
mos in Moscow there are less than half Russians it is
мос в Москве русских меньше половины это
not a Russian city  Who told you
не русский город Кто тебе такое сказал
that mos
что мос
look Yes this Look this is not a Russian
посмотри Да это Смотри это не русский
city all this is the city of all Okay good well
город всё это город всех Хорошо хорошо
done look I open
молодец вот смотри Я открываю
the Constitution of our Russian Federation it
Конституцию нашей Российской Федерации
says we are a multinational people of the
написано мы многонациональный народ
Russian Federation all his father suz
Российской Федерации всё его отец суз
lags Who did you tell your woman I
лаги Это ты кому своей бабе говорил я не
am not talking  with this I have an icon of
я разговариваю с этим у меня вот икона
Saint Nicholas hanging I am talking to him
висит Николай Угодник Я с ним
you are happy with this I understand
разговариваю тебя это устраивает понял
that is, you understood St. Nicholas
то есть ты на Николая Угодника понял
Listen, what faith do you worship, are you a
Слушай а ты какой Вере поклоняется ты
Christian or a Muslim?
христианин или мусульманин да Я
Yes, I am a Christian Well, you are a Tatar, I am
христианин Ну ты же нап татарин я
Orthodox, so what? And you are Orthodox, listen,
православ и что А ты православ слушай а
how do you feel about the fact that the temple is being seized?
как относи с тем что храм захватывают
Well, what kind of temple is seized in Ukraine? Orthodox, but to
Какие ну на Украине храм зах православ а
me  what does Ukraine have to do with it Well, what does it have to do with it You're
мне причём Украина Ну как причём Ты же
Ukrainian, what kind of Ukrainian I'm telling you I'm
украинец какой украинец Я тебе говорю я
from St. Petersburg And my father is a
из санкт-петербурга родом А у меня отец
Tatar, my mother is Russian I'm from
татарин мама русская Я из
St. Petersburg, what kind of Ukrainian
санктпетербурга какой украинец понял
I got it Got it Okay Vasilyevich I'll probably go
Понял поня Ладно Васильевич пойду
on, go right Yes,
наверно дальше иди правильно Да
good Oh, hello Oh, I know you Cool
хорошо О привет О я тебя знаю Прикольно
Are you on the toilet or something Oh, sorry, I
А ты на унитазе что ли О извини я это
went out to smoke, everything is fine, everything is
покурить вышел всё всё нормально
fine I just see toilet paper above
нормально Я просто вижу выше туалетная
And there on the left, what is it, you, it is at a
А вот там слева а что она аж вы она на
height, at a height, stop, if the doors are
высоте на высоте стоп подо если двери
there, then the toilet is in front of you, yes,
там то Унитаз перед тобой получается да
you are on the toilet  I put the phone on the
ты на унитазе поставил телефон да на
toilet lid. Yes, that's cool. Can you
крышке унитаза Да Прикольно А можешь
show me how? Well, I can't imagine. Aren't you
показать как Ну я не представляю Не
afraid that it
боишься что он
will fall?  who Well show me show me the toilet Well
упадёт кто Ну покажи покажи унитаз Ну
take the phone Show me the toilet I'm
возьми телефон Покажи унитаз мне
interested in how you installed the
интересно как ты поставил
phone it's not a phone it's a
телефон это не
laptop That's so cool Yes, yes,
ноутбук Вот так вот прикольно Дада нор
it's a laptop for you do
это ноутбук у теб
n't you understand one thing I'm renting an apartment the
не ты пойми одну вещь Я же Квартиру
landlord told me You can only smoke
снимаю мне хозяин сказал Курить только
in the toilet I smoke  in the toilet well
можно в туалете я курю в туалете ну
why why do I need this where will I go
зачем зачем мне вот это куда я поеду
then I understood Well I agree well he
потом понял Ну соглас ну он меня
asked me I told him well why would I like
попросил я ему ну зачем я буду его как
set him up the neighbors will be Why
бы вот подставлять соседи будут Зачем
smoke in the toilet I smoke in the toilet drunk
курить в туалете я курю в туалете пьяны
Well in the toilet smoke in the toilet That's how it is
Ну в туалете кури в туалете Вот так вот
and
и
accordingly And is this your laptop
соответственно А это у тебя ноутбук там
or
или
phone tablet and I think the tablet is
телефон планшет а планшет это думаю
wide yes Tablet you
широкий такой да Планшет ты планшет
put the tablet on the toilet tank Yes on top Well yes
поставил на на бачок унитаза Да наверх
yes You are absolutely right no not on the
Ну да да Ты абсолютно прав не не на
tank it is basically on the toilet I am and
бачок она в принципе на унитаз Я же а
Pony on this I  got it that is you put it
Поня на это я понял то есть ты поставил
on this one on the lid and ooh on the tank oh yeah damn
на этот на крышку и оёр на бачок о Да
cool that's exactly the same
блин прикольно там же как раз такой
technique there yeah really put it
приём есть Да реально положить
cool you lived in Russia how many years did you
классно ты в России жил сколько там лет
live in Russia what about Russia  I just know
в России жил причём России я просто знаю
how the toilet is where the lid opens Yes
как унитаз там где крышка открывается Да
there are a few tricks you put
там чуть-чуть приёмчики ты туда поставил
that
этот
NYFLA tablet there Why do I live in Finland
планшет нй фла Почему я в Финляндии живу
and what about it Yes Yam
а н чтоли Да Ям
Rom from Korea from the Soviet Union then
Ром из коре из Советского Союза потом
moved to
переехал в
Finland Listen Finns and when did you do this
Финляндию Слушай фины а когда вы это
debt Well  you will give us money for
долг Ну деньги отдавать нам будете за
genocide for the Armed Forces like Vyborg on Russians
геноцид за ВС как Выборге на русских
remember if I
помнишь я правильно
understand correctly I will tell you
понимаю я те расскажу
cop and from what is this Swedish city Yes it
копе а с какого это же шведский город Да
was originally You are dates on these What is it
был изначально Вы же финики по этим Как
called lived on their own there on
называется жили же по своим там по
small small small you did
маленьким маленьким маленьким вы города
not build cities  well, the Finns, the Finns specifically, the
не строили вот ну фины фины конкретно
Finns, they didn't build a single city, what
фины Ни один город не построили какой вы
city did you build, the Finns personally, the city,
город построили фины лично фины город
what are you,
какой ты ты какой город
what
построил фины Какой город построили
city did the Finns build? What city did you build, Helsinki, Tampa, Tinky - that's not your city?
Хельсинки тампе тинки - это не ваш город
And whose did the Swedes build? Oh, I get it. And
А чей это это шведы построили А понял А
what city did you build?  Well, let's say
какой вы город построили Ну допустим
Moscow is not Moscow, the Turks built it,
Москва не не Москва тюрки построили
the Tatars built it for you. What kind of Turks is
татары вам построили Какие какие тюрки
it that Moscow was built during the Tatar-Mongol yoke.
это во время татаро-монгольского ига
Khan Migu
построена Москва Хан Мигу
Timur is good, good, good. A  the rest And
Тимур хорошо хорошо хорошо А остальные А
Petersburg Who built Petersburg the Swedes
Петербург Кто построил Петербург шведы
the Swedes it Yes Peter I captured it simply
шведы его Да его захватил Пётр I просто
renamed it
переименовал
further Yes there was no city there
дальше Да там не было никакого города
Come on come on what other city was built
Давай давай какой город ещё построили
Come on at least one
Давай хоть один
Name what city was built at least one city
Назови Какой город построили хоть один
that the Russians built
город который русские построили
Name I tell you at least one city
Назови я тебе говорю хоть один город
that  you stand by the Finnish flag
кото стоишь по финским флагом
poin I have already named the Finnish cities
поин Я те п уже городов финских назвал
that the Finns built
которые фины постро
population
население
a half million
а полмиллиона
half a million
полмиллиона
GIM
гима
300000 And now you tell me man
300000 А теперь ты назови мне мужик
come on man on the toilet what city did you
давай мужик на унитазе какой ты город
build never in cities Finns did not live
построил никогда в городах Не жили фины
like Estonians in the
как эстон в
years your
годах твои
ancestors before not my  in the swamp In what
пред не мои предки на болоте В каких
cities did your ancestors live in the swamp then
городах жили твои предки на болоте то
about What cities are you talking about if your
про Какие города ты говоришь если твои
your great-grandfather even shorter he lived in a dugout
твой прадед ещё короче он в землянке жил
choice choice whose city Vyborg Finnish
выбор выбор чей город Выборг финский
city why is it suddenly Yes originally Finnish
город с чего он вдруг Да исконно финский
city
город
you why is it Finnish city tell me who are you
ты почему он финский город скажи ты кто
by
по
nationality I am Russian And where are your
национальности я русский А откуда твои
ancestors from, from what region are
родом предки из кой области
my Yes my princes  princes
мои Да мои князья князья
of Tver
тверские
and do you have any
а а у тебя есть какие-нибудь
princes I understand I understand Wait wait
князья понял Понял Вот подожди подожди
wait and who are you
подожди а ты кто
Finn do I understand correctly that the heir of the
Фин я правильно понимаю что наследник
Tver princes is sitting now smoking
тверских князей сидит сейчас курит
Tver prince I am Tver prince And who are
Тверской князь я Тверской князь А ты кто
you Tver prince Show your
ты Тверской князь Покажи свою
title you
титула ты
Tver you are being shown  Who are you
Тверской тебе тебе показывают Ты кто
so that you while you are the Tver prince
такой чтоб тебе пока ты Тверской князь
you are
ты
Tver under some flag
тверско под какого-то каким-то флагом
that the Russians came up with for you that's
который тебе русские придумали вот ты
who you are prince You first if you are a prince
кто такой князь Ты сначала если ты князь
Show your pedigree Show your coat of arms Where is
Покажи свою родословную Покажи герб Где
your coat of arms
твой герб
in front of me show me a prince without a coat of arms
перед м мне показывать князь без герба
is not a prince
не князь
you you are not a prince you are not a prince in front of you
ты ты не князь ты не князь перед к ты
really you are a prince
реально ты князь
Lord in front of whom should I show I am the
Повелитель перед кем мне показывать Я
king of
король
Finland wallo the third walla Trey walla
Финляндии валло третий валла Трей валла
tre
тре
Yes everything You are a prince prince you obey me
Да всё Ты князь князь ты мне это
because I am the king you are a prince
подчиняется потому что я король ты князь
Everything we bought you all you understand who
Всё мы вас всех купили ты понимаешь кто
you bought dude look you
ты купил чувак смотри тебе даже квартира
don't even own an apartment you even rent an apartment
не не принадлежит Ты даже квартиру
what can you buy in your
снимаешь Что ты можешь купить в своей
life I personally can how much  you have
жизни я лично я могу Сколько у тебя
a salary I can buy you How much is
зарплата я тебя купить могу Сколько у
your salary It doesn't matter what my
тебя зарплата Неважно какая у меня
salary is I will buy you Come on offer a
зарплата Я теб купить Давай предлагай
price I don't need to offer a price you
цену мне не надо цену предлагать ты
will offer a little don't understand
будешь предлагать немного не понимаешь
what is that damn I don't understand trade Yes
что тако блин не понимаю торговлю Да
explain to you
объясни тебе
Why well I'm just being honest
Да зачем ну просто я честно говорю
Okay  you really don't understand
Ладно ты ты реально не понимаешь Не
I don't understand I honestly don't understand how
понимаю я я честно я не понимаю как
the Heir to the Tver princes sits
Наследник князей тверских сидя
there with his legs spread out on a stash How does he want to
там на нычку Да как он хочет что-то
buy something in this
купить в этой
life in this life yes in this life
жизни в этой жизни да в этой жизни У
I have everything and what do you have
меня всё есть а у тебя что у тебя
you have everything Answer for your words You said that you
есть всё Ответь за базар Ты сказал что
have everything Show that you have everything you have a
всё есть Покажи что у тебя есть всё
car someone to whom Show you everything you
машина есть кому кому Показать тебе всё
see You you you you have nothing
видишь Ты ты у тебя у тебя ничего нет у
you don't even have your own apartment you
тебя даже квартиры нет своей ты не
can't sit and smoke in your
можешь сесть и покурить у себя в
apartment because  you don't have an apartment
квартире потому что у тебя нет квартиры
you have a landlord who
те н у тебя есть хозяин который
forbids you to smoke at home landlord
запрещает тебе курить дома хозяин У тебя
You have the truth you said so
есть правда ты так и сказал хозяин
landlord forbids Yes landlord forbids you see That
запрещает Да хозяин запрещает видишь То
is you have a
есть у тебя есть
Landlord you have something You have a
Хозяин у тебя что-то есть У тебя есть
Landlord I have my own  your apartment is the
Хозяин у меня есть своя квартира у тебя
owner  Your owner is your owner That
хозяин хозяин Хозяин у тебя хозяин То
is, you see his property, he
есть ты его собственность видишь он
gave you a place to smoke And you
тебе выделил место для курения Да и ты
smoke there, yes Yes, for the sake of interest, for the sake of
там кури да Да ради интереса ради
interest Show me your apartment Why, while
интереса Покажи свою квартиру Зачем пока
I am the king of Finland, I
Я король Финляндии какому-то тверскому
will show an apartment to some Tver prince,
князю буду показывать квартиру
you
ты
understand,
понял
okay, okay, let's do it normally  let's talk
давай ладно Давай нормально поговорим
normally for you come on I'm
давай нормально за тебя давай я вообще
not you me
не ты меня
I'm not from
Я не из
Finland And who am I from
Финляндии А сам кто я из
Vyborg the choice is Russian Yes I'm Russian myself
Выборга выбор русский Да я русский сам
Well it happens yes I hung the flag of Finland
Ну бывает да я повесил флаг Финляндии
because today is Independence Day of
потому что сегодня День независимости
Finland I want our choice to
Финляндии Я хочу чтобы наш выбор
return to Finland because  we
вернулся в Финляндию потому что нам при
lived
финнах жилось
better under the Finns, so you're right Well,
лучше так ты же
I don't know the USSR, but I know how
прих Ну я знаю ССР не жил но знаю как в
good it was in the USSR and I didn't live under Finland, you
ССР было хорошо и при Финляндии не жил
know, you're a Jew
зна ты еврей
grandma Yes, I'm a Jew and that I'm a Jew from
бабушка Да я еврей и что я еврей из
the sample I want to return to Finland and
выборка хочу вернуться в Финляндию и
that Israel is there
что Израиль Там
those
те я те
Now wait Israel
Сейчас подожди Израиль
country Hang this
страна Повесь это
Israeli flag no you're
израильский флаг не ты неправильно
doing it wrong there on the hairpin on the hairpins
делаешь там на заколка на заколках это
we already know the
мы уже в
course
курсе
Russian Armed Forces know So you're not Russian you're
русский ВС зна Так ты же не русский ты
Tverskoy and Tverski are not Russian No
Тверской а тверски не русски Нет
Tverski are not
тверские не
Russians still the most famous Tver do you know
русские ещ самый известный Твери знаешь
who zat mora gov he did not call himself
кто ж зат моря гово он не называл себя
Russian Mikhail Krug also did not call himself
русским Михаил Круг тоже не называл себя
Russian Who are
русским Кто
you Who are the Jews Come on Hava Nagila to
ты Кто такие евреи Давай Хава Нагила
you
тебе
Gila
Гила
what is this I have not seen yet
что такого я ещё не видел
just a dude
просто чувак
sits a little this Hv legs hugged
сидит маленько этой Хв ногами обнял
the toilet in short smoke
унитаз короче кури
shet Yes and he is the Heir to the
шет Да и он Наследник ля зей
Tver Finns
тверских фины
built Dude you your ancestors would have in short
построили Чувак ты твои предки б короче
for these princes did not even
за этими за князями даже не
clean up
убирали
Hello Hello I am from the city
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте я из города
exactly it turns out this is how would
именно получается это вот как
you formulate
бы вы Хмельницкого ли сформулировать
your
свой
question Khmelnitsky yes look here I mean here
вопрос да смотрите вот я имею в виду вот
from the point of view  view of T I am also the only one here on
с точки зрения Т меня тоже один тут по
history In short, how loaded in short
истории Короче как загрузил короче
completely bombed on the
полностью разбомбил по
facts I am specifically in
фактам я именно конкретно в
shock some kind of question Do you
шоки вопрос какой-то У вас
have yes Question exactly on the issue
есть да Вопрос именно как раз по вопросу
we talked and he me you know this
мы общались и он меня знаете вот это вот
I tell him like this on  fact and he me from
я ему говорю вот так по факту а он меня
above there
сверху там
Kievan Rus you understand
Киевской Руси понимаете
yes Question In what in
да Вопрос В чём
short well the question is what the question is that
короче ну вопрос в чём вопрос в том что
here you understand how it is like And you
вот понимаете как бы это поди А вы
blogger or
блогер что ли
something question What is your
какой-то вопрос В чём у
question Well, I have to understand with whom I am
вопрос Ну так я должен понимать с кем я
communicating block comn questions I am a historian
обща бло комн вопро я истори
I have been teaching at the university for 18 years in 2
Я преподаю в университете 18 лет через 2
years I will be
года будет
twentieth That's what it turns out Well, a
двадцатой Вот оно что оказывается Ну
historian is like yes these are people  I am writing a
историк это это как бы да это люди пишу
scientific Dita I have my scientific
научную Дита у меня мои научные
researchers touch upon the period of Kievan
исследователи касаются периода Киевской
Rus if this means anything to you yes
Руси если вам что-то это
yes yes I am interested in
говорит дадада меня вот интересует
a question concerning a little before Kievan
вопрос касательно немножечко до Киевской
Rus Maybe you know these moments
Руси Может быть вы знаете эти моменты
that the names concerning the tribe of Anty and not
что имен касательно ан племя Анты а не
Anty - this is not the tribe of Anty -  It was a
Анты - это не племя Анты - Это был
tribal
племенной
Union Well yes I heard Yes maybe you remember
Союз Ну да я слышал Да может помните
when the Goths Ostrogoths attacked the Antes there
когда готы остготы напали на антов было
was a prince mi Zamir he fought with the Goths Yes
был князь ми Замир он бился с готами Да
when miomir and 17 more Elders went to negotiate
когда Поехали на переговоры миомир и ещё
Yes the
17 Старейшин Да
Goths they went well with
готы они поехали ну с
persuasion and the Goths killed mimir and that's it
уговоров а готы убили мимира и се
The elders were greatly undermined by this then the
Старейшин это очень подорвало тогда
Andean
андский
union and then I remember It seems that these
союз а потом я помню Кажется их этих
Goths are the most gunas  the
готов самых гуны так же
same thing no no guna it was a little earlier
самое нет нет гуны это немножко раньше
like before a yes yes yes
было как раньше а да да да
Earlier a year then they kind of left
Раньше год потом они как бы ушли Их же
Someone kicked them out
кто-то выгнал Ну
Well go in Crimea no Look the thing is that in
го в Крыму нет Смотрите дело в том что в
Crimea there were Goths and Ostrogoths and
Крыму были готы да остготы э с
Germanic Yes they  and settled there the Gothic
германарих Да они там и осели готская
diocese of the Orthodox Church existed
епархия Православной Церкви существовала
until the 15th or 10th century by the way this is not clear I
до XV или X века кстати не это понятно я
mean in the territory there the
имею в виду вот на территории там
Dnieper region when year you there in the
приднепровье когда год ты там на
territory of the Dnieper region every
территории приднепровья каждый каждые
100 years the ethnic composition changed there
100 лет менялся этнический состав там
was this migration parallel
было это миграционная параллель
from east to west  yes, the Hungarians
из востока на запад была да то венгры
migrated there, the Bulgarians migrated there
туда мигрировали то Болгары мигрировали
yes, exactly the Goths, exactly the Goths, who
да Именно именно гото именно готов кто
expelled the Gugu, no one, look No, no, it was not the Huns who
изгнал гугу никто смотри Нет нет не гуны
expelled them They
изгнали Они раньше
left earlier, the Goths pushed back the Antes
ушли готово оттеснили Анты
and other
и ещё другие
tribes I read somewhere somewhere there, it
племена я где-то где-то я читал там то
seems like when it was  atil And on go not
вроде бы когда вот было атил И на го не
this not those are ready Look this those  the Goths
это не тех готов Смотри это те готы
who were in Germany West Goths
которые в Германии были Вест
visit in Germany I would know this but in
готов визи в Германии бы это я знаю но
my opinion somewhere I was here
по-моему где-то я вот
some other one was yes the battle of Attila with the
какую-то ещё было да битва атиллы с
Goths in the Teutoburg Forest the famous
готами в тевтобургском лесу известная
battle of the Goths Yes
битва готов Да
when the year and the polyur forest Teutoburg
когда год и полиур лесу тевтобургском
Forest Well I know  this battle there
лесу Ну я знаю эту битву там же не готы
would not be Goths no Are you talking about Varus who the Romans
бы нет Это вы про Вара который римляне
probably thought about the battle now yes yes
битву наверное сейчас подумали дадада да
yes yes that when did this Varr shout no
да то что когда ещё этот кричал варр не
le no Yes this These are different periods these are different
ле не Да это Это разные пери это разные
periods the forest is the same forest is the same
периоды лес тот же самый лес тот же
Yes and periods
самый Да а периоды
different Well there was a year I think it was no longer
разные Ну там год по-моему уже не было
there later they had already left there How did they leave Well
позже они там уже ушли было Как ушли Ну
those who are the Boer forest it is the same there the
те кто бурский лес это же это же там там
Saxon tribes lived there no year and they lived
племена саксов жили нет год и они жили
much
намного
tribes itself further north Well
племена сам севернее
well and the forest is on the territory of their
Да ну так и лес на территории ихнего
tribal  as if this Earth was nbr go
племенного как бы этого Земли был нбр го
goths they you no goths look goths go
готы они вы нет готы смотрите готы го
they were goths because of their expansion Yes
они были готы из-за своей экспансии Да
because goths here scientists now to this day
потому что готы вот учёные сейчас до сих
they argue What was the reason for the mass
пор спорят Что было причиной массового
reproduction of the Goths Yes, because there was a
размножения готов Да потому что был
German historian,
такой вот немецкий историк
uh, a fireman, I
ээ брандер
dont remember his last name, but his name is fireman
не помню как его фамилия но брандер его
Yes, he, he researched Yes, there was a
зовут Да он он исследовал Да что был
moment
момент
when the Gothic tribes developed en masse, that
когда готские племена массово разра то
is, something happened that led to
есть что-то случилось что привело к
the rapid  exponential
стремительному экспоненциальному
increase in the population of the Gothic tribes Yes and
увеличению населений готских племён Да и
because of this there was an expansion to the
из-за этого получилась экспансия на
east to the
восток на
west part went tried
запад часть пошла пробовала
read this but there are versions that there
читал это но есть есть версии что там
was a kind of warming
было как бы потепление
and too much something there, well, their
и слишком что-то там вот э
vegetation became stormy
растительность у них как бы пошла бурная
and they began to  many and they also
и них стали много и они отож там
multiplied there and
расплодились и
in short here is another Tai in Another version there
короче вот ещ Тай во Ещё ещё одна версия
is Well The thing is that I will not
такая есть Ну Дело в том что я не буду
say now whether it is right or
сейчас говорить правильно она или
wrong because this is not my
неправильно так Потому что это не моя
scientific field but there is such that the
научная область так но есть такая что
Gulf Stream is now a stream of currents  yes that
Гольфстрим вот сейчас шрим течени да то
is scientists believe that it changes
есть он учёные считают что он меняет
every so many years if it has a
каждые там сколько-то лет если у него
long cycle it changes its direction
длинный цикл Он меняет своё направление
so and
так и
uh that
ээ
means the Gulf Stream current is warm yes in
значит течение гольфстрима тёплые Да в
certain times there is such a theory
определённые времена есть такая теория
that the warm currents of the Atlantic
что Доплыл тёплые течения Атлантики
swam up to the Baltic Sea and so on and so
доплыли до Балтийского моря аж так вот и
when the next cycle was yes the next
когда очередной цикл был да очередной
cycle was when the Gulf Stream turned to
цикл был когда Гольфстрим повернул на
this warm Yes the territory of the
это тёплый Да территория
Germans began to warm up more so it
германских нача более прогреваться так
freezes less in the winter and more people
меньше замерзать зимой и больше людей
began to survive in these conditions  Yes, and they
стало выживать в этих условиях Да и
multiplied
расплодились
and they began agriculture Boshe They began Well,
и у них земледелие начало Боше Начали Ну
yes, and also this is such a moment, well, with the Goths It
да а ещ это такой момент ну с готами
is clear SN with the Goths regarding these
Понятно СН с готами касательно эти
sv Slavic tribes Yes Antes Antes
св славянские племена Да Анты Анты это
were essentially proto Slavs Yes, yes, yes, I know that
были прото славяне Да дада да это я знаю
I mean Slavic tribes When  there
Я имею виду славянские племена Когда уже
were already the Polyane, the
были вот поляне
Drevlyani, the Tivertsi, there are these White Croats, the
древляни тиверцы там эти белые хорваты
Volyn, this is what I have
волыне вот это вот у меня
Interestingly, the Vyatichi are such a tribe, you haven't
Интере Вятич такое племя вы ничего не
heard anything about the Vyatichi. The thing is, look,
слышали вятичи Дело в том что смотрите
the Vyatichi are not a tribe, the only one where there is no
вятичи Не есть племя единственное где не
tribe. I mean, there is like, well, like,
племя Я имею в виду там как бы ну как бы
relatively speaking  called yet Yes  look
условно говоря называло ещ Да смотрите
Vyatichi the only one where e was were remembered
Вятич единственное где э был были вспом
Vyatichi this is in the estate in the Tale of
нены вятичи это в помести В Повести
Bygone Years yes in the Tale of Bygone Years
временных лет да В Повести временных лет
that is Vyatichi were not e Slavs there
то есть вятичи не были ээ славянами не
was no this e Vyatichi and then they called more precisely
было это э Вятич и называли потом точнее
so Nestor the chronicler he is the only one who called it so
так Нестор летописец он единый кто так
Yes the territories of these e  finno-
назвал Да территории этих ээ фино
ugric uh tribes which in general
угорские ээ племена которые общим соте
collectively Vyatichi he
собирательным образом вятичи он их
called them yes that is so
назвал да то есть так
designated I remember Yes I read it somewhere
обозначили помню Да я я это где-то читал
I mean I remember Even if there is some kind of
Я имею в виду помню Даже ка какая-то
chronicle you know and there it is also
летопись есть знаете ли и там ещё
stated that in my opinion or  Yaroslav the Wise
указано что по-моему или Ярослав Мудрый
Well, one of these princes when he was traveling
Ну какой-то из этих князей когда он ехал
there in the direction of Yaroslavl
вот туда вот в сторону Ярославля туда
there and he was passing, I think, in the 10th century
вот туда и он проезжал по-моему в X веке
through the land of the Vyatichi, it was indicated that it was
через землю вятичей это было указано
some kind of heroic act that they
какой-то геройский поступок что они его
let him through and did not kill him  that is, these
как бы пропустили и не убили то есть эти
they were as if they were separate all
они как бы были получается отдельно всё
the time, one hundred wild Yes, they are wild, if you
время сто дикие Да они дикие вот если вы
remember Herodotus's
помните геродотов ские
andropharm  about androfarm people who were engaged in cannibalism there, all right, the territory that Herodotus describes, the settlement of androfarm describes, the places of settlement of the Vyatichi, then perhaps, perhaps, it turns out that they were like, but who baptized them? Well, look, the Vyatichi, yes, the Vyatichi, when Rus' came, it besieged Denmark, these like well not Slavic tribes not that I know I mean baptized them Yes if you look Yes the Vyatichi Vyatichi had Rebellions against the Slavs against baptism more than once they expelled there came Kato Iz e not Kato priest ty vki Yes in short in Finno-Gorsk such was not I mean that if in the 10th century, like they almost killed the prince, that is, it turns out that they werent part of Kievan Rus at all, they werent part of it. Yes, they were submissive to Kievan Rus and paid tribute to Kievan Rus, that is, there was no -that is precisely the cultural influence so that there is no Baptism of the church built by anyone Yes
андрофарм об
cultural influence Look, for example, how is it now in the Russian Federation Yes, for example, in Buryatia, you open schools in Russian There is this cultural influence, and there was a church there Yes, they forced people to go there and sing, in short, songs like there are all sorts of things on No, that was later later I mean in the times like the 11th century and the 10th century everything is simpler they came and installed a Governor by modern standards, like a prince who collects money, Tribute or Tyun, so he collected Tribute, in short, and transferred it to that's all. So they killed him, in short, and that's all. Well like yes there were such relations Yes I understand Well, okay, thank you go There is still no there are still interesting interesting topics Yes, you know, like the territory in the times of Rus' What was the name of the territory of the modern Moscow region of the Suzdal principality what did you read Just me I have no time I did it was called time not that under history evening on history always need to find time you understand me I have no time Now I have things to do at home time look it's all relative to the matter You can postpone matters urgent matters we have me there  boil boil boil potatoes there
меня там варится варится картофель там
salads potatoes look go
салаты картофель смотрите идите
Turn off potatoes we'll agree 10 minutes
Выключите картофель договорим 10 минут
then Turn on until boil really
потом Включите до варите реально
sorry wife will just kill me wife is
извиняюсь жена меня просто убьёт жена
normal less will be normal Well
нормально меньше будет всё нормально Ну
No sorry so to speak everything is
Нет извините так сказать все
ok write to my Telegram right now axis
уня пись на мий Telegram прямо зараз ось
VN
ВН
apok this is very and very important  YouTube is busy with
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through the scarg ORV in your ban and I
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
dont show a lot of videos to people at times I dont
багато видео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams Thats
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
why we Mali prompt connections
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
are written right now and Popik there in
пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там в
telegrams okrim videos are also interesting and
телеграми окрим видео ще теж цикава и
useful information and we are obliged to  you
корисна информация и мы повинни з вами
trimati permanent operational connection
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
independently in that chi will show you about this
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
write a
пиши а